Visual AIDS Artist Files
Visual AIDS Archive
- Mark Carter (1954–2005)
  Mark Carter was born in 1954 in Queens, New York. He received his GED and a college degree and had a career in nursing. After an accident resulted in his yearlong hospitalization he started to make art. He passed away in 2005.
  Mark Carter first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondences, a memorial program, artist bios, CVs, artist's statement, photocopies of press clippings, artwork, photocopies of artwork, photographs of artwork, periodicals, exhibition catalog, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1996-2005.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/mark-carter
  - Box 10 Folder 7 (Box 10)
  - Box 11, Folder 1 (Box 11)
- Gregg Cassin (b. 1958)
  Gregg Cassin was born in 1958 in New York. Gregg creates his art using found materials such as discarded/orphaned vintage photographs, old books, sacred imagery, sewing notions, and more. He lives between San Francisco and Sag Harbor, Long Island.
  Gregg Cassin first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain exhibition announcements, a CD with images of art, correspondence, ephemera, artist's statements and biography, reviews, press clippings, photocopies of press clippings, image lists, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1999-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/gregg-cassin
  - Box 11, Folder 3 (Box 11)
- Niccolo Cataldi (b. 1952)
  Niccolo Cataldi was born in 1952 in San Pedro de Macoris, Dominican Republic. Educated at la Escuela de Diseno in the Dominican Republic and Parson's School of Design in New York, he now resides in New York City. Cataldi is a sculptor and painter and has been exhibited widely in New York and the Dominican Republic.
  Niccolo Cataldi first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, postcards of artwork, correspondence, ephemera, exhibition catalogs, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, photocopies of collages, publications, CVs, photocopies of press clippings, CDs with images of art, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1997-2014.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/niccolo-cataldi
  - Box 11, Folder 4 (Box 11)
  - Box 11, Folder 5 (Box 11)
- Feliciano Centurion (1962–1996)
  Feliciano Centurion was born in 1962 in San Ignacio de las Misiones, Paraguay. He studied visual arts at the Escuela Nacional de Bellas Artes "Prilidiano Pueyrredon" in Argentina. His work includes painting, mixed media, and fiber arts and has been exhibited in Argentina and the US. He passed away in 1996.
  Materials pertaining to Feliciano Centurion include an exhibition program. This material is dated 2020.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/feliciano-centurion
  - Box 11, Folder 6 (Box 11)
- Walt Cessna (1964–2017)
  Walt Cessna was born in 1964. He was an artist, photographer, and author, as well as an editor, publisher, and curator. He passed away in 2017 in New York.
  Materials pertaining to Walt Cessna include a periodical dated 2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/walt-cessna
  - Box 11, Folder 7 (Box 11)
- Peter Cherone (1956–2010)
  Peter Cherone was born in 1956 in Patterson, New Jersey. Cherone was an artist and activist. He graduated from Pratt Institute with an MFA in Painting. He exhibited his work in New York, New Jersey, and Massachusetts. He died in 2010.
  Peter Cherone first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain exhibition announcements, artist statements, correspondence, CVs, photocopies of press clippings, calendar submission materials, photographic prints, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1991-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/peter-cherone
  - Box 12, Folder 1 (Box 12)
- H. Alan Cheung (1954–2003)
  H. Alan Cheung was born in 1954 in Shanghai, China. He studied at Taiwan Normal University and Otis Art Institute. His work was mixed media on paper and canvas and was shown in New York, California, and Taiwan. He passed away in 2003.
  H Alan Cheung first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition catalogs, CVs, an installation mock-up, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-1998.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/h.-alan-cheung
  - Box 12, Folder 2 (Box 12)
- Paul Chisholm (b. 1983)
  Paul Chisholm was born in 1983 in Canterbury, UK. He received a BA from Nottingham Trent University. Chisholm's practice has been featured on The BBC, The Daily Star, Metro Newspaper, Attitude magazine and more. He lives between Bletchingley in Surrey & Amsterdam, Holland.
  Paul Chisholm first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2010. They contain correspondence, a Postcards from the Edge submission, an artist's statement, CVs, and 35mm slide documentation of artwork with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2009-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/paul-chisholm
  - Box 12, Folder 3 (Box 12)
- Vincent Cianni (b. 1952)
  Vincent Cianni was born in 1952 in Scranton, Pennsylvania. He holds an MFA in Photography from SUNY New Paltz and teaches at Parsons, the New School for Design in New York City. He is photographing Newburgh, New York where he currently lives using traditional, analog photographic materials and cameras.
  Vincent Cianni first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain exhibition announcements, Postcards from the Edge submissions, ephemera, art periodicals, CVs, artist biographies, interview materials, exhibition materials, artist's statements, printouts of digital content, photocopies of periodicals, photographic prints, and 35mm slide documentation of artwork with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2001-2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/vincent-cianni
  - Box 12, Folder 5 (Box 12)
  - Box 12, Folder 6 (Box 12)
- Craig Coleman (1961–1995)
  Craig Coleman was born in 1961 in San Jose, California. He was a prominent figure in the New York downtown scene in the 80s. He moved to Miami and became involved with drag performance. He passed away in 1994 in Miami.
  Materials pertaining to Craig Coleman were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain a CD with images of art, correspondence, a CV, an artist's biography, photographic documentation of artwork, and a 35mm slide of artwork. These materials are dated 1983-1998.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/craig-coleman
  - Box 13, Folder 2 (Box 13)
  - Box A, Folder 5 (Box A)
- Michael K. Colgan (1958–1993)
  Michael K Colgan was born in 1958 in Coronado, California. He graduated from George Mason University, in Fairfax County, Virginia, with a bachelor of arts degree. He worked in advertising and graphic design for many years. His work was exhibited across the country. He passed away in 1993.
  Materials pertaining to Michael K Colgan were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive by James Colgan in 1999. They contain an artist biography, correspondence, calendar submission materials, press clippings, lists of artworks, a CV, copies of press clippings, and 35mm slide documentation of artworks with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1981-2001.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/michael-colgan
  - Box 13, Folder 4 (Box 13)
- Ms. Colombia (1954–2018)
  Ms Colombia (born Oswaldo Gomez) was born in 1954 in Medellin, Colombia. She moved to New York in the 1970s and was a colorful performance artist based in Jackson Heights, Queens. She received a bachelor's degree in Engineering and a master's in law from York University. She entertained crowds with colorful outfits based on her Colombian heritage. She was known as the Queen of Riis Park and the Queen of Queens. She passed away in 2018.
  Materials pertaining to Ms Colombia include an exhibition announcement. This material is dated 2019.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/ms-colombia
  - Box 37, Folder 11 (Box 37)
- Shirlene Cooper
  Shirlene Cooper is an HIV activist from Brooklyn, New York. She started and runs the Women's Empowerment Art Therapy Group with Visual AIDS. She is an advocate for women living with HIV and is the first African American woman living with HIV to sit on New York City Council's HIV/AIDS Service Administrations Advisory Board. She has traveled to 46 states and 31 countries with her activism. She lives in Brooklyn, New York.
  Materials pertaining to Shirlene Cooper include a periodical and photographic prints. These materials are dated 2021-2022.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/shirlene-cooper
  - Box 70, Folder 6 (Box 70)
- Carlos Cordero (b. 1975)
  Carlos Cordero was born in 1975 in the Dominican Republic. He studied art at SUNY Purchase where he discovered printmaking. His work has been exhibited widely in both solo and group exhibitions. Carlos now lives and works in his studio in Coney Island, New York.
  Carlos Cordero first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2014. They contain grant materials and Postcards from the Edge submission materials. These items are dated 2014-2022.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/carlos-cordero
  - Box 13, Folder 5 (Box 13)
- Harold Cortes (1958–1996)
  Harold Cortes was born in 1958 in Cali, Colombia. He studied jewelry design and designed jewelry for Broadway shows and other productions in New York. He focused his full attention on painting and worked on several mural works with his partner, Gregory Maskwa. He also painted sets for Broadway. He was awarded a plaque for his art for the Presidential Proclamation for World AIDS Day in 1994. He passed away in 1996.
  Materials pertaining to Harold Cortes include memorial materials, correspondence, an artist's biography, artist's statements, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1996-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/harold-cortes
  - Box 13, Folder 7 (Box 13)
- Jose Luis Cortes (b. 1962)
  José Luis Cortés was born in 1962 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania to Puerto Rican parents. They moved to Puerto Rico where he lived until the age of 28, when he moved to New York City. His artistic career took off more when he began producing work inspired by the 1990s New York City gay scene. His work has been exhibited in galleries and museums in the US and internationally. He lives and works in Puerto Rico.
  Jose Luis Cortes first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, photographic prints, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition promotional materials, photocopies of press clippings, CVs, and periodicals. These materials are dated 1994-2007.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jose-luis-cortes
  - Box 13, Folder 8 (Box 13)
  - Box 13, Folder 9 (Box 13)
- Bob Corti (b. 1951)
  Bob Corti was born in 1951 in New York. He received a BFA from Queens College and an MFA in photography and painting from Boston University. He moved to San Francisco where he was an artist in residence, a teacher, and where his art was exhibited widely.
  Bob Corti first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, a CV, periodicals, calendar submission materials, correspondence, photographs, an artist's statement, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1996-2001.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/bob-corti
  - Box 13, Folder 10 (Box 13)
- Steven Cortiella (b. 1957)
  Steven Cortiella was born in 1957 in Brooklyn, New York. He started creating art as a child, and has been a designer and in health care for most of his working life. He lives in Brooklyn.
  Steven Cortiella first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, photographs of artwork, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1999-2002.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/steven-cortiella
  - Box 13, Folder 11 (Box 13)
- Harold Cousar (b. 1951)
  Harold Cousar was born in 1951 in Brooklyn, New York. He studied at The Washington Business Institute.
  Harold Cousar first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They contain photocopies of drawings and photographs. These materials are dated 2004.
  - Box 13, Folder 13 (Box 13)
- Max Coyer (1954–1988)
  Max Coyer was born in 1954 in Hartford, Connecticut. He studied poetry at Trinity College in Hartford, Connecticut, before moving to New York City in 1980 to pursue visual arts. He worked primarily in painting, blnding both academic and modernist art movements. His work has been exhibited in New York as well as in Baltimore and Los Angeles. He passed away in 1988.
  Materials pertaining to Max Coyer were donated to the Visual AIDS archive by Paula Pierce in 2023. They contain exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, press releases, and ephemera. These materials are dated 1985-1993.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/max-coyer
  - Box 70, Folder 13 (Box 70)
- Peter Cramer (b. 1957)
  Peter Cramer was born in 1957. He is the co-founder, artistic, and administrative director of Le Petit Versailles community garden in the East Village. He is known for cross-disciplinary multimedia work including experimental film, documentary, and diaristic approach. His work also includes photography, installation, and performance. With his longstanding partner and collaborator Jack Waters he co-established Allied Productions Inc., a non-profit arts umbrella, in 1981. They also served as directors of ABC No Rio alternative art collective from 1983 to 1990. His work has been exhibited widely in the US and internationally. He lives in New York.
  Materials pertaining to Peter Cramer include Postcards from the Edge submission materials, a photo book, a CD with images of art, exhibition program, and a publication. These materials are dated 2008-2019.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/peter-cramer
  - Box A, Folder 6 (Box A)
- Bruce Cratsley (1944–1998)
  Bruce Cratsley was born in 1944 in Canton, New York. He studied in Esslingen, West Germany, as well as at Swarthmore College, the University of Pennsylvania, and the New School. He worked in galleries and as a photographer. His photographs are held in the Brooklyn Museum, the New York Public Library, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Boston Museum of Fine Arts, and the Bibliotheque National in Paris. He passed away in 1998.
  Materials pertaining to Bruce Cratsley were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999 by Sarah Morthland. They contain exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, artist's statements, artist's biography, correspondence, photocopies of press clippings, press releases, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1976-1997.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/bruce-cratsley
  - Box 13, Folder 14 (Box 13)
  - Box 14, Folder 1 (Box 14)
- Brian Crede (b. 1952)
  Brian Crede was born in 1952 in New York City. He graduated from Kent State University with a degree in industrial design and a minor in copper enameling. He works with paper and three-dimensional art. He moved to Fort Lauderdale in 2014. His artwork is in private collections around the US and France.
  Brian Crede first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain CDs with images of art, exhibition announcements, CVs, artist's statements, correspondence, printouts of art, printouts of digital content, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1998-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/brian-crede
  - Box 14, Folder 2 (Box 14)
- Lucretia Crichlow (1950–1997)
  Lucretia Crichlow was born in 1950 in the Bronx. She took night classes at the Fashion Institute of Technology while attending community college before becoming a full time student there. She worked for buying offices at fashion companies, and later for designers. She also did freelance fashion illustration. Her work is illustration on paper. She passed away in 1997.
  Materials pertaining to Lucretia Crichlow were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Loretta White. They contain 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying labels. These materials are dated 1990-1994.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/lucretia-crichlow
  - Box 14, Folder 3 (Box 14)
- Preston Cros (b. 1970)
  Preston Cros was born in 1970 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. He is a self-taught artist whose work is primarily in photography.
  Preston Cros first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They contain a CD with images of artwork with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2009.
  - Box 14, Folder 4 (Box 14)
- Ben Cuevas (b. 1987)
  Ben Cuevas was born in 1987 in Southern California. He received a BA in mixed media, installation, and photography at Hampshire College. He works primarily in textiles. It has been exhibited in Los Angeles and New York, and has also been featured in several books and publications.
  Materials pertaining to Ben Cuevas include an exhibition program and periodicals. These materials are dated 2014-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/ben-cuevas
  - Box 14, Folder 5 (Box 14)
- William Cullum (1958–2020)
  William Cullum was born in 1958 in San Diego, California. He primarily produced paintings and works on paper. After spending some time incarcerated, he started a blog about that time and his experience as an artist afterwards. He passed away in 2020 in New York City.
  William Cullum first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1994. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, photocopies of press clippings, various image lists, ephemera, and 35mm slide documentation of artwork with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1994-1999.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/william-cullum
  - Box 14, Folder 6 (Box 14)
- Vincent D'Arata
  Vincent D'Arata studied various arts at the Culinary Institute of America, in Hyde Park, New York, Miami Dade College, St. Peters University in Jersey City, New Jersey, and The New School in New York. His work is primarily in painting, sculpture, and digital collage. It has been exhibited in New York.
  Vincent D'Arata first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They contain CDs with images of art, exhibition announcements, and grant application materials. These materials are dated 2006-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/vincent-darata
  - Box 14, Folder 7 (Box 14)
- David Cannon Dashiell (1952–1993)
  David Cannon Dashiell was born in 1952 in Tokyo, Japan. He received both a BFA and MFA from Cal Arts and worked there with John Baldessari. His work was exhibited extensively in California and New York, as well as other places around the country. His works are in the San Francisco MOMA, the University Art Museum Berkeley, the Whitney Museum of American Art, as well as private collections. He passed away in 1993 in San Francisco.
  Materials pertaining to David Cannon Dashiell were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2007 by Sono Osato. They contain a CV, a bibliography, a posthumous biography, correspondence, exhibition materials, photocopies of press clippings and periodicals, a portfolio, a CD with images and a video, small printouts of "Queer Mysteries", posthumous Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, publications, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1986-2005.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-cannon-dashiell
  - Box 14, Folder 8 (Box 14)
  - Box 14, Folder 9 (Box 14)
  - Box A, Folder 8 (Box A)
  - Box A, Folder 9 (Box A)
- Patrick De Castro
  Patrick de Castro was born in Haiti. He studied interior design at Pratt Institute before moving to Miami. His work includes painting, collage, and mixed media.
  Materials pertaining to Patrick De Castro include Postcards from the Edge submission materials.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/patrick-de-castro
  - Box 15, Folder 1 (Box 15)
- Joe De Hoyos (b. 1962)
  Joe De Hoyos was born in 1962 in Houston, Texas. He attended the University of Houston majoring in graphic communications. He started to work with collage and moved to New York City in 1993 and maintained a studio in his living space. He currently lives in Palm Springs, California.
  Joe De Hoyos first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, CVs, an artist's bio, calendar submission materials, a newsletter, photocopies of artwork, periodicals, ephemera, CDs with images of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1987-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/joe-de-hoyos
  - Box 15, Folder 2 (Box 15)
- Jason Deneault (b. 1948)
  Jason Deneault was born in 1948 in Hanover, New Hampshire. Educated at Emerson College in Boston, Massachusetts, he also was trained in massage therapy and professional dance. His work with collage has been exhibited primarily in Massachusetts and New York. He lives in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
  Jason Deneault first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain exhibition announcements, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, artist's statements, CVs, calendar submission materials, correspondence, a photocopy of an artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1986-2004.
  - Box 15, Folder 3 (Box 15)
- Jimmy DeSana (1950–1990)
  Jimmy De Sana was born in 1949 and grew up in suburban Atlanta, Georgia. He graduated from Georgia State University in 1972 where he started pursuing photography. He moved to New York shortly after graduating college. He was a key figure in the East Village punk art scene of the 1970s and 1980s and photographed prominent creatives for album covers and alternative publications. William S. Burroughs wrote the introduction to his collection of photographs Submission which was self-published in 1980. He passed away in 1990.
  Materials pertaining to Jimmy DeSana were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Laurie Simmons. They contain exhibition announcements, a CV, a page from an exhibition catalog, a press clipping, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1977-2010.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jimmy-de-sana
  - Box 15, Folder 6 (Box 15)
- Dan Diamond
  Dan Diamond grew up in Michigan and has been painting since adolescence. His work is primarily in abstract painting.
  Materials pertaining to Dan Diamond include correspondence, a photocopy of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1994-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/dan-diamond
  - Box 15, Folder 7 (Box 15)
- Angelho G Diaz (b. 1966)
  Angelho Diaz was born in 1966 in Havana, Cuba. As a child he took classes in painting, acting, vocal ensemble, instrumental groups, theatre, and others. After studying internationally, he returned to Havana to become a professional pianist. His visual art is a combination of painting, photography, and collage.
  Angelho Diaz first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2019. They include an artist's biography, and printouts of artwork. These materials are dated 2017-2019.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/an-gelho-d
  - Box 15, Folder 8 (Box 15)
- Francisco Diaz (b. 1950)
  Francisco Diaz was born in 1950 in Puerto Rico and raised in New York. He became a street artist to support his family. His art includes crafts, building wooden houses, ships, kitchen decorations, greeting cards, and works on paper.